Email: ARashed07@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmed-rashed-12495a20

https://aithub.com/ahmedlrashed

Phone: (781) 309-7560

Professional Summary

Certified LabVIEW Architect & TestStand software engineer specializing in automated test development, code optimization, and data analytics and visualization. My goal is to transfer my data mining, analysis, and visualization skills from the manufacturing industry to the business intelligence and data analysis field. I hope to leverage my passion for optimization, automated processing, and reliability to a role that allows me to make a difference in the lives of others.

Technical Skills

- LabVIEW (expert/architect)
- Python (intermediate)
- Data Extract & Transform
- TestStand (expert)
- R (intermediate)
- Data Analysis & Visualization
- Agile Workflow JIRA (expert)
- SQL (intermediate)
- SW Versioning (Git/Perforce)

Certifications

- Certified LabVIEW Architect (2014)
- Certified LabVIEW Developer (2012)
- Google Data Analytics Certificate (2023)
- Google Advanced Data Analytics Certificate (WIP)

Work Experience

HENNY PENNY

Data Analytics Consultant

• Eaton, OH

• 03/2023 - present

- Created generic database extractor for viewing production data, publishing it to the company web app for manufacturing engineers to improve product and process performance.
- Led development and rollout of internal real-time SPC system for the production floor.

HENNY PENNY

LabVIEW-TestStand Consultant

• Eaton, OH

• 11/2022 - 02/2023

- Enhanced configuration and report management, creating portable test limits and custom data visualizations, enabling on-the-fly configuration changes in minutes not hours.
- Debugged and improved TestStand sequences and their underlying LabVIEW code modules for functionality and repeatability, boosting yield from 65% to 99%.
- Restructured TestStand project and its dependencies, allowing one-click distribution and deployment to multiple stations, reducing test station setup time from 3 days to 2 hours.

GRANVILLE - PHILLIPS

LabVIEW-TestStand Consultant

- Broomfield, CO
- 09/2022 01/2023
- Optimized Python data analysis package for general use, empowering line operators to see, understand, and act upon real-time statistical process data without constantly referring to manufacturing engineers.
- Added EtherCAT communication functionality to the 352 Ion Gauge test system using LabVIEW Object Oriented Programming, doubling test stand capacity.

• Updated TestStand sequencer system for robustness, improving pass-fail rate from 75% to 95%.

MKS INSTRUMENTS

LabVIEW Consultant

- Methuen, MA
- 07/2022 10/2022
- Reverse-engineered VoDM test application from LabWindows/CVI and re-wrote the test software into an extensible sub-panel LabVIEW framework.
- Designed LabVIEW test software to run semi-automatically, allowing a single line operator to run five stands simultaneously, improving productivity and tack time four-fold.

MKS INSTRUMENTS

Principal Test Engineer

- Methuen, MA
- 03/2021 06/2022
- Managed software engineering projects (leading teams of 2 4 developers) for test station software, guiding junior developers and chairing code reviews and feedback sessions.
- Setup standardized JIRA workflows and trained team-mates on how to use these workflows, improving project visibility and allowing the team to efficiently cover twice as many issues in our weekly meetings.
- Enhanced centralized database connectivity and statistical process control, allowing manufacturing engineers to see trends in production lots and make data-driven decisions from the factory floor.

MKS INSTRUMENTS

Senior Test Engineer

• Methuen, MA

• 09/2011 - 02/2021

- Created and published interactive Tableau dashboards for direct access to real-time data. Trained operators, manufacturing engineers, and business unit managers how to use these dashboards.
- Developed LabVIEW web service driver to connect all product lines to a central database, allowing engineers and line operators to catch process issues in hours rather than days.
- Upgraded and overhauled several legacy product lines through reverse-engineering the original engineering code and rewriting the test software into a production-ready LabVIEW framework.

MKS INSTRUMENTS

Test Engineer

• Methuen, MA

• 06/2008 - 08/2011

- Wrote from scratch an automated LabVIEW test software GUI for the stability test of FTIR spectrometers, reducing unit cycle time from 19 days to 12 days.
- Addressed production issues on the floor. Kaizen blitz and FMEA analysis to find root causes of test stand failures and implementing short- and long-term solutions.

Education

Master of Arts: Physics BRYN MAWR COLLEGE, Bryn Mawr, PA **Bachelor of Science: Applied Physics**UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND, Baltimore, MD